Software Developer DANIEL KROISS





+43 677 62 66 0336
Hamburg, DE (soon Salzburg, AT)
daniel_kroiss@gmx.at
linkedin.com/in/daniel-kroiß

ABOUT ME

As an Austrian developer who spent several years in Hamburg, I now find myself yearning for the Austrian Alps again. I am currently looking for new opportunities to pursue my passion for frontend development and be able to contribute effectively to a company that resonates with my values.

I'm enthusiastic about writing well-structured, scalable, and maintainable code. I'm highly self-motivated, reliable, and value open communication. In my spare time you can find me travelling to different countries trying to find the most scenic hikes to explore with the scottish highlands being an all-time favourite of mine;-)



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Otto GmbH & Co. KG, since February 2022 [TS, Svelte, Jest, Selenium, Kotlin, Java, MongoDB, AWS]

- Building a micro-service architecture to provide highlyscalable and maintainable after-sales experience
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams ensuring a sharp customer focus
- Implementing frontend optimizations by diving into new technology, e.g. Svelte, web-components, vite

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Wertstatt8 GmbH (Energie AG), Apr 2021 - Jan 2022 [Node.js, React, Azure, Firebase, Node-RED, Figma, Jira]

- Prototyping IoT solutions (ambient assisted living) ensuring safe aging based on power consumption data through anomaly detection via machine learning in collaboration with external stakeholders
- MVP focused project development

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Raiffeisen Software GmbH , Sept 2019 - Apr 2021 [Angular, Java, MongoDB, Kubernetes, Zeplin]

- Building automated investment-software to make financial investments available and accessible to everybody
- Collaborating with the Enabler Team on a complete rebuild of the user interface and migrating from Angular.js to Angular
- Developing and maintaining online banking software with a special focus on accessibility

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER - INTERN

W4 Premium Web GmbH, Aug 2018 - Jan 2019 [Angular, PWA, PHP, Typo3]

- PWA development with CMS integration
- Clarifying client requirements
- Conducted CMS trainings for customers

DISPATCHER

A1 Telekom Austria AG, 2014 - 2016

- Task planning and assignment control
- Customer service
- Efficiently coordinated and dispatched service requests

CIVILIAN SERVICE

Lebenshilfe OÖ, 2013 - 2014

Supporting people with disabilities in their work environment

EDUCATION

BACHELOR STUDIES - COMMUNICATION AND KNOWLEDGE MEDIA

FH Hagenberg University of Applied Sciences, 2016 - 2019

- Full stack development, user experience design and E-Learning
- Bachelor thesis I: "Progressive Web App Develop once, run many".
- Bachelor thesis II: "NoSQL Alternative Datenbanken für den Webbereich" (Alternative databases for the web)

ENGINEERING HIGH SCHOOL - ELECTRONICS

HTL Leonding 2012 - 2016

• Apprenticeship with A Level

APPRENTICESHIP - COMMUNICATION TECHNICIAN

A1 Telekom Austria AG, 2009 - 2013

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Angular, Svelte, Vue and TypeScript Reactive programming HTML5 and CSS3 Automated testing frameworks Node.js and npm Java, Kotlin (Spring ecosystem) SQL and NoSQL databases GIT

AWS

Continuous integration and delivery Microservices architecture Monitoring Systems